Tijo Thomas

Location:India Email: tjo.thomaz@gmail.com

Phone: +91 9605645591 LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tijo-j-thomaz93

PROFILE

Passionate Front-End Engineer with 5+ years of experience, with a goal to find solutions for different domains with my expertise and meet the requirements of the organization. Focused on writing optimized and good quality code and trying to deliver client satisfaction work. An enthusiastic learner who quickly grasps new concepts and technical skills.

TECHNICAL SKILLS SUMMARY

- HTML
- CSS
- Javascript
- Typescript
- Graphql(Client)
- Node js (Static-Client)
- React Js
- Angular
- Redux
- Ngrx
- Charts/Highcharts
- Aws DynamoDb

- SCSS
- Material UI
- React Native
- Aws Serverless
- Marko.Js
- Styled Component

CAREER SUMMARY

Infosys Limited Senior Associate Consultant

May 2021 - present

Outline

Worked as Lead developer for Reporting Tool for the store Associate and Leaders, that will be used to track the progress of Associate and E-commerce platform, Focused on the development for payment section in View item module, integration of Klarna and Escrow payment UI

Client :Home Depot Key Responsibility

- Integrated the SSO Authentication with ping fed
 - Connect the standalone application to the toolbelt from Home Depot inc
 - Followed SCSS partials for integrations with Home Depot custom utility classes
- Managed team of 4 frontend developer by providing insights and reviewing code for code quality

Client: Ebay Inc

Kev Responsibility

- Worked on the UI for Klarna and escrow in eBay, View Item module
- Worked in the development of marko.js packages in npm for eBay registry
- Worked for the UI eBay Motors UI payment section

NetObjex Software Engineer

May 2020 - May 2021

Outline

Worked as Lead developer for creating covid pre auth portal for the employee onboarding to the company

Key Responsibility

- React hooks implementation for Project structuring
- Rematch implementation for state management.
- Highcharts is for time series chart generation.
- Styled components with material UI stylings for css.
- Modularizing the reusable components.
- Implementing Apollo client for graphql api

Qburst Technologies Software Engineer

Nov 2018 - Mar 2021

Outline

Worked as UI Developer for location tracking portal for tracking the users with the mobile application and Parking cloud application for finding spaces in the parking lot censor

Client: Riscovery Key Responsibility

- Implementations of google maps API.
- React hooks implementation for map components
- Chart Is for time series chart generation.
- Plotting polygon and shapes using google maps and functionality.

Client: All Traffic Solutions

Key Responsibility

- Implementation of Serverless Application Modeling using AWS services.
- AWS amplify CLI for the fast development process client-side with ReactNative Elements for building UI.
- Implementation simple document database using AWS Dynamodb service.
- Implementation of frequent fetching of availability using AWS Cloudwatch Cron job scheduler.
- Implementation of AWS API gateway and REST service with AWS Lambda endpoints.

Speridian(Pankanis) Technologies

Nov 2016- Jul 2018

Associate Trainee

Outline

Worked as Associate Trainee for developing a chrome extension for the client

Client: Gogo Business Aviation

Key Responsibility

- Implementation of React chrome extension with manifest JSON
- Chrome console setup for calculating the network hits and data.
- Creating a bridge between the chrome extension and react native app. .
- Connecting to s3 bucket data api and running in html video tag and calculating the buffer time
- Calculating the hits to the given website for the change in the speed matrix

EDUCATION

Master of Computer Applications

Aug 2014 - Nov 2016

M.G.University Kottayam, India

Bachelor of Computer Applications

May 2011 - Jul 2014

M.G.University Kottayam, India